this problem requires that
we use an if else statement to run a
loop that prints
the loop was processed one time if
process the loop equals true otherwise
print the loop wasn't processed
process the loop is a local variable
initialized on line one and
every time we run our program process
the loop will be set to reference
either the boolean true or the boolean
false
we have an array with two elements true
and false
and we call sample which is an array
method
on this array sample will return
a random element out of that array
and in this particular code the return
value of calling sample
on the array is what is assigned to that
local variable process the loop
this might seem a little confusing so
let's just output the value
of process the loop
[Music]
so we've run our program once and we can
see that false was assigned to process
the loop
[Music]
and on the fourth time that we run our
program you can see that process the
loop reference
is true
[Music]
so now that we know what's happening on
line one we can move forward with coding
up a solution
the problem description tells us that we
need to use an
if else statement
so let's just kind of write out the
bones here
[Music]
now if process the loop is equal to true
we want to run a loop that prints the
loop was processed one time
so what we can do is
use process the loop is equal to true
as the conditional of our if statement
now we could output the loop was
processed one time without actually
creating a loop
but to meet the problem requirements
let's put this within a loop
[Music]
so within the block pass to the loop
method we
will output the loop was processed and
the instructions here specifically tell
us that we just want to print the string
one time
so we'll go ahead and place a break on
line
six so that our loop will only execute
one time
going back to the problem description if
process the loop
is not equal to true we want to output
the string
the loop wasn't processed
and let's just run our code and see what
we've got
[Music]
it looks like the first time through
process the loop was set to reference
false
and so we output the string the loop
wasn't processed
and the next time we went our program we
output the loop was processed
everything appears to be working
appropriately but just to ensure that it
is
we can actually
[Music]
print process the loop so we can see its
value
next to the output of our program
so the first time we run our program we
see that the value of process the loop
is false
and we have the appropriate output
the next time through process the loop
is true
and we see the appropriate output for
that as well
so everything's working as expected now
one important thing to know
is that we don't actually need to
perform this comparison with true on
line five
ruby will evaluate the value that
process the loop references
and if it evaluates to true lines
6 through 9 the first branch of our if
statement will be executed
if it evaluates to false then the else
branch of our if statement will be
executed
without the comparison let's run our
code again
and see that it still works
[Music]
you can see that it's still working as
expected
when the value of process the loop is
false
we print the loop wasn't processed when
the value is true we print the loop was
processed
[Music]
and we can remove this line from our
code now that we know it's working
properly
and our code will run according to the
problem requirements